

VIVIAN SARA MANDIZVIDZA

21 Harry Pichanick Drive

Alexandra Park

Harare

Zimbabwe

Telephone: (263-242) 748518-21 (Office) Cell: +263 77 443 5064/+263 77 222 6202

E-mail: vivmand17@gmail.com, vmandizvidza@noic.co.zw

PERSONAL PROFILE

Nationality: Zimbabwean

Languages: English, Shona and Ndebele

A. BACKGROUND

I have more than 25 years' experience in the legal field, 11 as a public prosecutor in the Magistrates Court, Regional Courts and later in the High Court. I also had a short stint in private practice, before joining the City of Harare as a Legal Officer and later appointed the Chief Legal Officer of the City of Harare. I worked as the Legal Advisor/Acting Company Secretary for NOCZIM (Private) Limited and later joined ZB Financial Holdings as the Head, Legal & Compliance Services. I am currently the Company Secretary/Corporate Services Director for the National Oil Infrastructure Company of Zimbabwe (Private) Limited. I am a holder of a Bachelor of Laws (Hons) and a Masters in Business Administration, both from the University of Zimbabwe. Have worked for the past 15 years as an inhouse/corporate lawyer, overseeing issues of compliance and corporate governance.

B. COMPETENCIES

- Self-initiator and team player
- ♣ Strong analytical skills and results oriented
- ♣ Ability to interact at all levels in diverse organizational environments.

C. EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

1. CURRENT EMPLOYER: NATIONAL OIL INFRASTRUCTURE COMPANY OF ZIMBABWE (NOIC) (PVT) LTD

POSITION: COMPANY SECRETARY/CORPORATE SERVICES DIRECTOR

AUGUST 2015 TO DATE

Duties:

- Providing corporate secretariat services for the company and its two subsidiaries.
- ♠ Management and coordination of all corporate events.
- ♣ Ensuring that the Company is compliant with all corporate governance requirements
 ♣ Providing leadership for the legal department.
- Providing legal advice to the board and all departments of the Company, including liaison with external lawyers to ensure that the company's interests are protected.
- Properties that the Company is compliant with all legal requirements in its operations.
- ♦ Negotiating and drafting contracts on behalf of the Company. ♦ Heading the Public Relations and Procurement divisions.

2. PREVIOUS EMPLOYER: ZB FINANCIAL HOLDINGS LIMITED

POSITION: ASSISTANT COMPANY SECRETARY

APRIL 2011 TO AUGUST 2015

Duties:

- Providing company secretariat services.
- ♣ Ensuring that the company's annual returns are up to date. ♣ Providing leadership for the legal department.
- Providing legal advice to the board and all departments of the Company, including liaison with external lawyers to ensure that the company's interests are protected.
- Ensuring that the Company is compliant with all legal requirements in its operations.
 Negotiating and drafting contracts on behalf of the Company.
 - 3. PREVIOUS EMPLOYER: NATIONAL OIL COMPANY OF ZIMBABWE (NOCZIM) (PVT) LTD

POSITION: LEGAL ADVISOR

JAN 2009 TO APRIL 2011

ACTING COMPANY SECRETARY June 2010 to April 2011

Duties:

- Providing company secretariat services.
- Preparation of scheduled Board meetings, Extraordinary Board meetings, Annual and Extraordinary General Meetings.
- ♣ Ensuring that the Company's Annual Returns are up to date.
- Providing legal advice to the Board and all departments of the Company, including liaison with external lawyers to ensure that the Company's interests are protected.
- Ensuring that the Company is compliant with all legal requirements in its operations.

- Negotiating and Drafting contracts on behalf of the Company.
- **†** Chairing Disciplinary Hearings.

4. PREVIOUS EMPLOYER: CITY OF HARARE

4.1 POSITION: CHIEF LEGAL OFFICER

NOV 2006 TO DEC 2008

- Providing secretarial services to the Council and heading the Legal Division.
- Administration of Tender Procedures in line with Council Policy and other legal requirements.
- Liaising with Council's external legal practitioners to ensure that matters handed to them are handled appropriately and in the best interests of the Council.
- ☆ Chairing Disciplinary Hearings.

4.2 POSITION: LEGAL OFFICER

2004 TO 2006

- Providing legal services to Council including advising Council in meetings and council departments in their day to day operations.
- 4 Appearing in the Magistrate, Labour and Administrative Courts on behalf of Council.

5. PREVIOUS EMPLOYER: KWENDA AND ASSOCIATES

POSITION: LEGAL PRACTITIONER

2004 TO 2004

Providing comprehensive legal advisory services to clients in a private law firm.

6. PREVIOUS EMPLOYER: MIN. OF JUSTICE, LEGAL & PARLIAMENTARY AFFAIRS

6.1 POSITION: PRINCIPAL LAW OFFICER, ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OFFICE

2002 TO 2004

Prosecuting criminal cases in the High Court of Zimbabwe.

6.2 POSITION: PUBLIC PROSECUTOR, ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OFFICE

1992 TO 2002

Prosecuting criminal cases in the Magistrates Courts of Zimbabwe.

D. EDUCATIONAL AND PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

- 1. Institution: University of Zimbabwe (UZ) 2006 to 2011
 - → Programme: Master of Business Administration
- 2. Institution: Judicial College of Zimbabwe 2005 to 2005
 - Programme: Legal Drafters' CourseAward: Legal Drafters' Certificate

- 3. Institution: University of Zimbabwe (U.Z) 1999 to 2002
 - → Programme: Bachelor of Laws Honours Degree (Llbs. Hons.)
 - → Awards: University Book Prize (2002)
- 4. Institution: Domboshawa National Training Centre 1991 to 1992
 - ◆ Programme: Public Prosecutor's Course
 - + Award: Prosecutor's Certificate
 - 5. Institution: Montrose Girls' High School 1984 to 1989
 - → Programme: Secondary School Education

E. MEMBERSHIP TO PROFESSIONAL BODIES AND BOARDS

- (1) Law Society of Zimbabwe
- (2) Zimbabwe Women Lawyers Association
- (3) Past Chairman of Christian Care Zimbabwe Board
- (4) Board Member of Reformed Church University

F. REFERENCES

MR. C U KANDEMIIRI

MR. C T KATHEMBA

CHAMBER SECRETARY
TOWN HOUSE, CITY OF HARARE
HARARE, ZIMBABWE

E-MAIL: cukandemiiri@hararecity.co.zw PHONE: +(263-242) 781810-6 MOBILE: +263 71 286 4356

MS. T MANGEZI

FORMER GROUP COMPANY SECRETARY
ZB FINANCIAL HOLDINGS LIMITED
HARARE, ZIMBABWE

E-MAIL: ctkathemba@gmail.com MOBLIE: +263 77 343 7390

JUSTICE P. KWENDA

IPG ZIMBABWE HARARE, ZIMBABWE

E-MAIL: tmangezi@ipgzim.co.zw PHONE: +(263-242) 752339 MOBILE: +263 71 240 3947 HIGH COURT OF ZIMBABWE HARARE, ZIMBABWE E-MAIL:

kwendapisirai@yahoo.com MOBILE: +263 71 254 2700